The manuscripts to both books are here in the archive collections at
Turku Academy Library.
Welcome to the Turku Academy Library and Edvard Westermarck's archive collections.
We are very proud to have stored them for more than sixty years:
Letter, Manuscript, Pictures, etc.
Westermarck retained the drafts of many of his books, speeches and lectures,
And he seems to have been a bit of a perfectionist to judge by all the corrections in the lyrics.
Westermarck also left a collection of 7500 letters,
Carefully cataloged here at the Turku Academy Library.
His letter collection contains correspondence with some of his
Time's most famous anthropologists.
Last week I had seminars two days in a row, which ended with
A tea party for twenty people.
I have never had a more satisfactory term at school. "
Edvard Westermarck's large image collection contains some photographs from his
Occupational and home environments in Finland and England, but the majority of the pictures are from Morocco.
Photography was one of the most important methods used by Westermarck
in his extensive field work in Morocco.
These images provide an excellent presentation of field research conditions at the end
of the 19th and early 1900s
Westermarck focused its field research on customs and beliefs in Morocco,
And he wrote several books on the subject.
One of his primary interests was "Baraka" which is a concept of holiness.
In his field work, Westermarck wanted to be able to get his information directly from
the informants, and therefore learned Arabic and also studied one of
Amazighdials, Shilha or Tashelhit.